<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nischal Shrestha</title>
    <link>http://nischalshrestha.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nischal Shrestha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:36:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://nischalshrestha.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning learnr: a primer.</title>
      <link>http://nischalshrestha.me/blog/learnr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nischalshrestha.me/blog/learnr/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a blog post on the RStudio Education blog about how to reason about the learnr. I outline the basic architecture and the tech stacks involved with learnr and a &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; way to think about the package.
In the second post, I will dive into the details behind the experience adding multi-language support, and setup code chaining. I will also talk about recent Python challenges for exercise checking in the third post, so keep an eye out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://nischalshrestha.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nischalshrestha.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Nischal is a PhD student at NC State University. His research interests lie in the intersection of human-computer interaction, software engineering and programming languages. In particular, Nischal researches new instructional techniques and tools that can help programmers learn programming languages effectively and efficiently. Nischal works with Chris Parnin in the alt-code lab.
 Recently, Nischal has been working on literate programming for building tutorials. In the summer of 2020, Nischal worked on learnr at RStudio with Alison Hill and Greg Wilson, adding exercise support for Python (and other languages) as well as the ability to chain setup code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://nischalshrestha.me/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nischalshrestha.me/projects/</guid>
      <description>pygradethis  pygradethis is a Python autograder to facilitate code output and static code checking. This package is inspired by Daniel Chen&amp;rsquo;s gradethis. It is designed to be minimal and can be used for Python only, or within learnr for Python exercise checking through the gradethispython R wrapper package.
 py2r   An interactive lesson using learnr which can be used to teach Python programmers the basics of dataframe manipulation in R (base or tidyverse).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://nischalshrestha.me/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nischalshrestha.me/publications/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar
2021  Remote, but connected: How #TidyTuesday Provides an Online Community of Practice for Data Scientists. Nischal Shrestha, Titus Barik and Chris Parnin. CSCW 2021: 24th ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing
Preprint
 Through semi-structured interviews with 26 data scientists, we uncovered motivations behind their participation in #TidyTuesday, how the project benefited them, and how it cultivated an online CoP.
 2020  Here We Go Again: Why Is It Difficult for Developers to Learn Another Programming Language?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://nischalshrestha.me/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nischalshrestha.me/teaching/</guid>
      <description>2019  CSC 116: Introduction to Computing - Java
 I taught an introductory course in computer science using Java, which I really enjoyed! It was the first time I was in full charge of lecturing, making exams and trying out live coding in front of the class.
 2018  Mentor for REU (Research Experience for Undergraduates)
 I mentored Colton Botta who went on to use his research skills to collaborate with me on my ICSE paper!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>